Guide to the William Winlock Miller Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- W. W. Miller, 1845-83; Series I; (7 boxes)
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Incoming letters
      - Stevens, Isaac I., 1860 (Box 5, Folder 282)
      - Stevens, Isaac I., 1861, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 283)
      - Stevens, Margaret L. (Hazard) [Mrs. Isaac I. Stevens], 1862-64, n.y. (Box 5, Folder 284)
      - Stevens, Oliver, 1858-61 (Box 5, Folder 285)
      - Strang, Thomas and William, 1852 (Box 5, Folder 286)
      - Strong, James C., 1853 (Box 5, Folder 287)
      - Struve, Henry G., 1873 (Box 5, Folder 288)
      - Stuart, A. H. H. [Washington Emigration Society], 1875 (Box 5, Folder 289)
      - Stuart, R. G., 1869, 1870 (Box 5, Folder 290)
      - Swan, James G., 1859-63 (Box 5, Folder 291)
      - Swindall, Calvin W., 1858-61 (Box 5, Folder 292)
      - Tennant, John A., 1859-60 (Box 5, Folder 293)
      - Terry, Charles C., 1860 (Box 5, Folder 294)
      - Tilton, J., 1856-74 (Box 5, Folder 295)
      - Tolmie, W. F., 1852-72, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 296)
      - Townly, W., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 297)
      - Treasury Department, 1851-59 (Box 5, Folder 298)
      - Treasury Department, 1861-73 (Box 5, Folder 299)
      - Tucker, C. H., 1863 (Box 5, Folder 300)
      - Turner, J. T., 1858-66 (Box 5, Folder 301)
      - Turney, L. J. S., 1863 (Box 5, Folder 302)
      - Turpin, E. A., 1857-58 (Box 5, Folder 303)
      - Turpin, Peterfield, 1863-67 (Box 5, Folder 304)
      - U.S. Sanitary Commission [Berry Collins, Francis Fowler], 1863-64 (Box 5, Folder 305)
      - Van Bokkelen, J. J. H., 1857-59 (Box 5, Folder 306)
      - Van Cleave, I. S. M., 1859-63 (Box 5, Folder 307)
      - Van Valzah, I. M., 1860 (Box 5, Folder 308)
      - Vinson, W. D., 1852 (Box 5, Folder 309)
      - Walker, R. M., 1866 (Box 5, Folder 310)
      - Wallace, W. H., 1862, 1864 (Box 5, Folder 311)
      - Walton, W. N., 1863 (Box 5, Folder 312)
      - Ward, W. Wallace, 1856 (Box 5, Folder 313)
      - Weed, Charles E., 1856 (Box 5, Folder 314)
      - Weeks, F. L., 1860 (Box 5, Folder 315)
      - Wells Fargo and Co., 1866 (Box 5, Folder 316)
      - Wells, William P., 1856-63 (Box 5, Folder 317)
      - Whitcome, J. B, 1867 (Box 5, Folder 318)
      - Williams, E., 1862 (Box 5, Folder 319)
      - Williams, G., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 320)
      - Williamson, James E., 1856 (Box 5, Folder 321)
      - Wills, John A., 1856 (Box 5, Folder 322)
      - Wills, William J., 1854-55 (Box 5, Folder 323)
      - Wilson, F. A., 1865 (Box 5, Folder 324)
      - Wilson, Henry C., 1852-62 (Box 5, Folder 325)
      - Winlock, Robert S., 1859 (Box 5, Folder 326)
      - Winlock, William Henry (after W. W. Miller's death, 1876), 1883 (Box 5, Folder 327)
      - Woodson, A. G., 1861 (Box 5, Folder 328)
      - Wright, William, 1863-64 (Box 5, Folder 329)
      - Wyche, J. E., 1872 (Box 5, Folder 330)
      - Yantz, A. S., 1872 (Box 5, Folder 331)
      - Yates, Rich, 1852-55 (Box 5, Folder 332)
      - Unidentified, 1852-72 (Box 5, Folder 333)
    - Outgoing letters
      - Biddle, B. Robert, 1854 (Box 6, Folder 334)
      - Biles, J., 1861 (Box 6, Folder 335)
      - Billows, The Rev. Henry, 1862-63 (Box 6, Folder 336)
      - Buchanan, President, 1860, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 337)
      - Cain, A. J., 1859 (Box 6, Folder 338)
      - Carver, M. M. M., 1870 (Box 6, Folder 339)
      - Corwin, Thomas, 1851 (Box 6, Folder 340)
      - Denny, A. A., 1866 (Box 6, Folder 341)
      - Department of Interior [D. S. Maynard], 1857 (Box 6, Folder 342)
      - Dole, W. P., 1864 (Box 6, Folder 343)
      - Douglas, Sir James, 1851 (Box 6, Folder 344)
      - Douglas, Stephen A., 1852 (Box 6, Folder 345)
      - Fitzhugh, E. C., 1859 (Box 6, Folder 346)
      - Frost, 1859 (Box 6, Folder 347)
      - Garfield, S., 1870 (Box 6, Folder 348)
      - Geary, Edward R., 1860 (Box 6, Folder 349)
      - Gibbs, George, 1865, 1867 (Box 6, Folder 350)
      - Goswell, W. B., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 351)
      - Griswold, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 352)
      - Holliday, Ben, 1869 (Box 6, Folder 353)
      - Kelly, William, 1860 (Box 6, Folder 354)
      - Kendull, B. F., 1860 (Box 6, Folder 355)
      - Kennedy, James K., 1867 (Box 6, Folder 356)
      - Ladu, James B., 1859 (Box 6, Folder 357)
      - Lane, Joseph, 1859 (Box 6, Folder 358)
      - Logan, P., 1851 (Box 6, Folder 359)
      - McElroy, T. F., 1868 (Box 6, Folder 360)
      - McFadden, O. B, 1858-73 (Box 6, Folder 361)
      - Mason, C. H., 1858 (Box 6, Folder 362)
      - Matthias, Frank, 1859 (Box 6, Folder 363)
      - Miller, Robert [brother] (on the death of Joseph Winlock), 1858 (Box 6, Folder 364)
      - Monat, W. A., 1852 (Box 6, Folder 365)
      - Moses, S. P., 1851-52 (Box 6, Folder 366)
      - Rutherford, Alan, 1874 (Box 6, Folder 367)
      - Slaughter, W. A., 1855 (Box 6, Folder 368)
      - Smith, S. D., 1869 (Box 6, Folder 369)
      - Steel, A. H., 1873 (Box 6, Folder 370)
      - Stevens, Mrs., 1866 (Box 6, Folder 371)
      - Stevens, O., 1859 (Box 6, Folder 372)
      - Thompson, Jacob, 1858 (Box 6, Folder 373)
      - Tolmie, W. F., 1851-56, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 374)
      - Treasury Department (R. J. Atkinson), 1858-64 (Box 6, Folder 375)
      - Ward, W. Wallace, 1856 (Box 6, Folder 376)
      - Whittlesey, Elisha, 1851 (Box 6, Folder 377)
      - Wiley, Aron, 1852 (Box 6, Folder 378)
      - Work, Lititia, 1853-54 (Box 6, Folder 379)
      - Yates, Richard, 1852 (Box 6, Folder 380)
      - Unidentified, 1852, 1860 (Box 6, Folder 381)
  - PAPERS
    - Accounts and Business Papers
      - Surveyor and Inspector of Revenue for the port of Nisqually, 1850-52 (Box 6, Folder 382)
      - Surveyor and Inspector of Revenue for the port of Nisqually, 1852-53 (Box 6, Folder 383)
      - Surveyor and Inspector of Revenue for the port of Nisqually, 1853-54 (Box 6, Folder 384)
      - District Courts, Oregon and Washington Territories, 1852-60, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 385)
      - Quarter Master's Department, 1856-57 (Box 6, Folder 386)
      - Quarter Master's Department, 1857 (Box 6, Folder 387)
      - Quarter Master's Department, 1858 (Box 6, Folder 388)
      - Quarter Master's Department, 1859-68, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 389)
      - Superintendent of Indian Affairs, 1861 (Box 7, Folder 390)
      - Superintendent of Indian Affairs, 1861-62 (Box 7, Folder 391)
      - Washington Territory fund for the relief of sick and disabled soldiers, 1862-63, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 392)
      - Washington Territory fund for the relief of sick and disabled soldiers (Box 7, Folder 393)
    - Agreements
      - To send scholars to be taught by W. W. Miller, 1850 (Box 7, Folder 394)
      - House purchase and lease, W. W. Miller and M. T. Simmons, 1852 (Box 7, Folder 395)
      - (Memorandum) between W. W. Miller, M. T. Simmons, H. A. Goldsborough and J. B. Gosnell, to build and operate a sawmill, 1853 (Box 7, Folder 396)
      - (Memorandum) between W. W. Miller and H. A. Goldsborough (original and copy), 1853 (Box 7, Folder 397)
      - Subscription to a woolen manufactory, 1864 (Box 7, Folder 398)
      - Authorisation, Central Corresponding Committee, Washington Territory (Box 7, Folder 399)
    - Appointments
      - Surveyor and Inspector of the Revenue for the port of Nisqually by President Fillmore, and Bond: W. W. Miller, 1851 (Box 7, Folder 400)
      - Deputy United States Marshal, Puget's Sound, Oregon Territory, 1852 (Box 7, Folder 401)
      - Master Commissioner in Chancery District Court, 3rd Judicial District of Thurston County, 1853 (Box 7, Folder 402)
      - Deputy Collector of Customs and Inspector of Revenue for Puget Sound, plus Oath of acceptance, 1853 (Box 7, Folder 403)
      - Quarter Master General of the Militia, Washington Territory, 1857 (Box 7, Folder 404)
      - Notary Public, Second Judicial District of Washington Territory, 1857 (Box 7, Folder 405)
      - Quarter Master General of the Militia, Washington Territory, 1858 (Box 7, Folder 406)
      - Joint councilman, Thurston and Sawamish Counties, 1858 (Box 7, Folder 407)
      - Notary Public, Second Judicial District, Washington Territory, 1861 (Box 7, Folder 408)
      - Superintendent of Indian Affairs, Washington Territory, by President Buchanan, 1861 (Box 7, Folder 409)
      - Mayor of Olympia, 1872 (Box 7, Folder 410)
    - Articles
      - "The Conscription Act," by George B. Butler, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 411)
      - "Goes a begging" [by W. W. Miller?], [1860?] (Box 7, Folder 412)
    - Certificates
      - Teaching, 1845-49 (Box 7, Folder 413)
      - License, cattle broker, 1862 (Box 7, Folder 414)
      - Master Mason, 1863-65 (Box 7, Folder 415)
    - Financial Material
      - Miscellaneous, 1858-60, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 416)
    - Photographs
      - W. W. Miller, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 417)
    - Receipts
      - Miscellaneous, 1856-60 (Box 7, Folder 418)
      - Miscellaneous, 1860 (Box 7, Folder 419)
      - Miscellaneous, 1860-62, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 420)
      - Deputy Collector of Internal Revenue, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 421)
      - Estate of Edward Furste, 1865-66 (Box 7, Folder 422)
      - Coal Creek Road Company, 1867 (Box 7, Folder 423)
- I. I. Stevens, 1853-62; Series II; (1 box)
  The series is divided into two subseries: Correspondence and Writings. Correspondence contains letters received by I. I. Stevens, arranged alphabetically by the name of the writer of the letter, and chronologically within each folder. These letters are followed by one letter written by I. I. Stevens. (His letters to W. W. Miller appear in Series I). The Writings subseries contains three items written by I. I. Stevens, arranged alphabetically by category.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Incoming letters
      - Curtis, S. B., 1861 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Democratic Party, 1860 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Gallup, Charles, 1861 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Gillet, R. H., 1861 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Hardy, Epps, 1861 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Larcombe and English, 1860 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - McFadden, O. B., 1860 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Millard, M. B., 1861 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Miller, Caleb, 1861 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Miller, W. W., 1855-58 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Miller, W. W., 1858-60 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Nesmith, J. W., 1861 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Paige, G. A., 1861 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Schmitt, Fr., 1861 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Smith, A. J., 1857 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Stanton, Fred J., 1862 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Stevens, Hazard, [1861] (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - W. T., 1856 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Tilton, James, 1858 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Tilton, Mrs. J., 1861 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Treasury Department (J. J. D. Fuller), 1861 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Unidentified, 1861 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Outgoing letter
      - President Franklin Pierce (copy), 1856 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - WRITINGS
    - Article and notes, rejoinder to Chenoweth (copy) (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Resolutions, (copy? by I. I. Stevens?), [1858? or 1888?] (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Will, draft, 1853 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Special Files, 1848-1958; Series III; (3 boxes)
  Series III, Special Files, contains papers, including correspondence and manuscripts, of persons other than W. W. Miller or I. I. Stevens. The papers concern the activities of Miller and Stevens, the Washington Territory generally, and the early history of the Pacific Northwest. The series is divided into three subseries: Correspondence, Writings and Subjects. Correspondence contains letters arranged alphabetically by the name of the person to whom the letter is addressed, and chronologically within each folder. These are followed by letters to unknown persons, arranged alphabetically by the name of the writer of the letter, where this is of some note, and chronologically within each folder. Writings are arranged alphabetically by the name of the author; each author's writings are arranged alphabetically by category and alphabetically by title within each category. The Subjects subseries is arranged alphabetically by category, and alphabetically by subject within each category.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Adams, S. W., 1863 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, J. Patton, 1856 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Armstrong, C. H., 1860 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Arnold, Mr. (re: A. Lincoln), 1866 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Bagley, D., 1864 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Black, Judge (Attorney General), 1858 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Buchanan, President (Petitions), 1857-59, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Carson, J., 1866 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Cisco, J. J., 1863 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Clark, 1869 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Clarke, F. A., 1862 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Cook, A. G., 1870 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Corwin, Thomas (Secretary of the Treasury), 1851 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Counsel and House of Representatives, Washington Territory (Petition), 1859 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Douglas, Sir James, 1851 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Douglas, S. A., 1857 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Doyle, R. B, 1855 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Durgan, L., 1861 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Ebey, I. N., 1853-55 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Evans, Elwood, 1863-95, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Francis, S., 1865 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - French, Emily and Nancy, 1856 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Frost, Morris H., 1859 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Furste, Edward, 1860 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Geary, E. R. (Superintendent of Indian Affairs) (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Gholson, Gov. R. D., 1860 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Gibbs, George, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Goshwell, W. B. (Indian agent, Olympia), 1861 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Gove, Warren, 1858, [1859?] (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Harding, Senator B. F., 1863 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Henry, Francis, 1865-88 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Jackson, J. R., n.y. (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Judson, John P., 1874 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Kelly, William D., 1864 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Lander, Edward, 1857 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Lane, Richard, 1861 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Lansdale, Doctor R. H., 1855 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Laws, John and Thomas, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Legislative Assembly, Washington Territory, 1859 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Lock [Winlock Miller?], 1937-38 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - McCaw, T., 1862 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - McElroy, T. F., 1853-69 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - McElroy, H. B., 1888 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - McFadden, Mrs. Margaret, 1875 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - McFadden, Obadiah B., 1858-74 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - McFadden, R. N., 1890 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Maynard, D. S., 1857 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Medill, Hon. W., 1860 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Miller, Mrs. Mary M., 1879-91, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Miller, Pendleton, 1858 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Miller, Winlock W. (Sr.), 1927, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Murphy, John M., 1862 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Nesmith, I. W., 1861 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Newell, Caroline A., 1874 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Olympia Lodge No. 1, 1859 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Piers, H. N., 1856 (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Poe, A. M, 1853 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Post Master General (petitions), 1861-67 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - Post Master General, from Abraham Lincoln (xerox copy), 1864 (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - Rutledge, William, 1857 (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - Simmons, M. T., 1852-53 (Box 9, Folder 61)
    - Staeger, Carl P. (enclosing article by Mrs. Forney on O. B. McFadden), 1927 (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - [Stevens, Mrs. Isaac I.], 1863 (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - Strong, George T., 1863 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Strong, William, 1852 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Struve, H. G., 1868-72, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - Struve, Mrs. H. G., 1863-67 (Box 9, Folder 67)
    - Struve, Mrs. H. G., 1868-70 (Box 9, Folder 68)
    - Struve, Mrs. H. G., 1870-72 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    - Struve, Mrs. H. G, 1872, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - Thompson, Jacob, 1858 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - Tolmie, W. F., 1851-60 (Box 10, Folder 72)
    - Van [Bockelen?], 1862 (Box 10, Folder 73)
    - Wiley, J. W. ("Pioneer and Democrat"), 1856 (Box 10, Folder 74)
    - Wilson, John, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - Winston, 1860 (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - Yates, Richard, 1853-60 (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - From [Granville O. Haller?] to [his mother?], n.y. (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - From O. B. McFadden to unidentified, 1860 (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - Unidentified, 1853-72, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - WRITINGS
    - Brooks, Charles I., poem, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Evans, Elwood, address, "The Discovery of the Columbia River and Adjacent Territory" (newspaper clipping) (Box 10, Folder 82)
    - Evans, Elwood, address, on the 86th Anniversary of American Independence, 1862 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Evans, Elwood, address, to the Washington State Historical Society (typewritten), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - Evans, Elwood, article, "Did Marcus Whitman save Oregon to the United States?" (typewritten), 1885 (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - Evans, Elwood (article? -- on Indians) (Box 10, Folder 86)
    - Evans, Elwood (article? -- on Oregon, typewritten), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 87)
    - Evans, Elwood (article?) -- "The San Juan Archipelago", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 88)
    - Evans, Elwood (article?) -- "What We Want", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 89)
    - Evans, Elwood (article?) -- fragments, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 90)
    - Evans, Elwood (notebook) (draft of speeches?), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 91)
    - Fremont, John C., Geographical Memoir upon Upper California (printed), 1848 (Box 10, Folder 92)
    - Haller, Granville O., notes on the anti-Chinese riots in Seattle (on back of photograph), [1886] (Box 10, Folder 93)
    - Henry, Francis, article, "The People's Loss" (death of O. B. McFadden, typewritten copy), 1875 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    - Henry, Francis, notes (on citizens' meeting, Olympia, on Northern Pacific Railroad), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 95)
    - Henry, Francis, notes (on Washington), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 96)
    - Henry, Francis, poem, "The Old Settler" (mss. and three printed copies, published 1902, 1914) (Box 10, Folder 97)
    - Henry, Francis, poem, "The Oregon Pioneer" (published 15 Jun 1876) (Box 10, Folder 98)
    - Henry, Francis, poems, "Alki," "Lines on the Death of a Pioneer," "A Node on the Double Load," "Tacoma," "Tom Pilkins," "What Is It?", no title, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 99)
    - Miller, Winlock, Jr., compilation of pioneer reminiscences (on death of Joseph Winlock) (Box 10, Folder 100)
    - Miller, Winlock, Jr., Introduction, anonymous volume of pioneer reminiscences, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 101)
    - Miller, Winlock, Jr., notebook and four typed copies, "W. W. Miller" (Box 10, Folder 102)
    - Miller, Winlock, Jr., notes (incomplete) and typed copy (on W. W. Miller) (Box 10, Folder 103)
    - G. B. S., biographical sketch, Simon Plomondon (local Indian agent, Cowlitz Landing W. T.), 1933 (Box 10, Folder 104)
    - Whiting, J. S., articles, notes and photographs of drawings, (on Forts), 1933 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - SUBJECTS
    - Alki Camp No. 2 (constitution and menu), 1899-1902 (Box 11, Folder 106)
    - Bill (copy, requesting the vote of the people of the Territory of Washington, relative to the seat of Government, with vote by Elwood Evans), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 107)
    - Bills, Memorials and Resolutions, House of Representatives, Washington Territory (Box 11, Folder 108)
    - Biographical
      - Dr. Griscom, Col. B. F. Shaw, "Pop" Smith, home of Nathan Eaton, home of T. F. McElroy, papers from McElroy estate, unknown (photographs), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 109)
      - O. B. McFadden (military discharge, tributes on death), 1856-75 (Box 11, Folder 110)
      - O. B. McFadden, Swartz and Caldwell families, including Mrs. McFadden (notes) (Box 11, Folder 111)
      - W. W. Miller (newspaper clippings), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 112)
      - W. W. Miller, Jr. (newspaper clippings), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 113)
    - Circular, Gallatin and Elizabeth Hartstock (accusing Elwood Evans, their attorney), 1860 (Box 11, Folder 114)
    - Financial material, miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 115)
    - Historical
      - Alaska (newspaper clippings and advertisement for bonds of the Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition) (Box 11, Folder 116)
      - Canada (newspaper clippings), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 117)
      - North Pacific Railroad (newspaper clippings and printed material) (Box 11, Folder 118)
      - Olympia (newspaper clippings), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 119)
      - Olympia (notes), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 120)
      - Pioneer reminiscences (newspaper clippings), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 121)
      - Washington Territory (Daily Olympian, Golden Jubilee Edition, Pioneer section), 1939 (Box 11, Folder 122)
      - Washington Territory (newspaper clippings, pamphlet on Lake Washington Canal, pamphlet advertising Washington to immigrants), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 123)
    - Land claims, George W. Scholl, William P. Perkins, 1852-65 (Box 11, Folder 124)
    - Land sales
      - Edmund Sylvester ("Founder of Olympia"), 1854, 1864 (Box 11, Folder 125)
      - Joseph W. Phillips to Sarah M. Renton, 1861 (Box 11, Folder 126)
    - Lists
      - Books in library of W. W. Miller, at his death, 1876 (Box 11, Folder 127)
      - Officers and Board of Managers, Washington National Monument Society, 1852 (Box 11, Folder 128)
    - Military discharge, W. Ward, 1856 (Box 11, Folder 129)
    - Muster role, militia volunteers, Olympia (including E. Evans, I. I. Stevens, H. G. Struve), 1861 (Box 11, Folder 130)
    - Newspapers, Washington Review and Examiner; Daily Intelligencer, Vol. 1, No. 2, (copy?); Morning Olympian-Tribune, 1875-93 (Box 11, Folder 131)
    - Printed matter, miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 132)
    - Puget Sound Steamship Company, agreements, plans, and business papers, 1858-59, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 133)
    - Resolutions (copy by C. H. Mason, re: I. I. Stevens' proclamation of martial law), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 134)
    - Statement, Mount Rainier Fund (Winlock Miller), 1924 (Box 11, Folder 135)
    - U.F.F.U. (a secret society established in Olympia about 1869), constitution, ceremonies, notebook, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 136)
    - Unidentified, notebook and fragments, 1900, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 137)